Seema. S

Paralegal (US Immigration)

Contact

556 A, Iboo Sait Bungalow Ranni Medu House Coonoor 643-102 The Nilgiris, Tamil Nadu +91 8072855732 +91 8754851554 officialseema2021@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/seema-sait

Legal Assisting Skills

Law Office Support
Legal Research
Records Management
Word Processing
Data Entry
Spreadsheet Management
Database Management
INSZoom
ImmPro
Flag portal (LCA)

Computer Skills

Adobe
MS Word
Excel
Outlook
SharePoint

Key Skills

Innovative Thinking
Attention to Detail
Team Leadership
Initiative Driven
Adaptability
Time Management

Profile

Driven to maintain ethical standards while providing top-notch assistance to attorney. An experienced (3+ years) Immigration Paralegal seeking work in the same capacity to deliver relevant expertise gained through case documentation, and processing. Common threads in my employment history include prioritizing work, providing excellent service and satisfaction, analyzing processes and increasing efficiency.

Experiences

Envoy Global India Pvt. Ltd. (Hyderabad, India)

Paralegal • March 2023—Present

- Engaging in U.S. immigration law for non-immigrant and immigrant visas.
- Organizing petition packets for review and filing.
- Processing H-1B, H-4, H-1B CAP Registration, Employment based Green Card, Family based Green Card, TN, I-140, Change of Status, N-400, G4 UN Child & G4 UN Retiree, NVC (DS-260 and DS-160).
- Managing the caseload from intake through processing and filing.
- Reviewing applications for accuracy prior to submission to United States Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS).

CheriCo Legal Services d/b/a CheriCo IT Services (Coonoor, The Nilgiris, India)

Legal Assistant • November 2019—February 2023

 Focusing on various aspects of U.S. immigration law for nonimmigrant and immigrant visas on behalf of multinational clients including technology, management consulting, and pharmaceutical companies.

Activities and Interests

Walking Riding Driving

- Processing and filing visa petitions and applications for H-1B & H-4, Registering for H-1B CAP, Employment based Green Card (EBGC), Family based Green Card (FBGC), TN, I-140, N-400, G4 (UN Child & UN Retiree), NVC (DS-260 and DS-160).
- Managing the caseload from intake through processing and filing.
- Organizing petition packets for review and filing.
- Responding to immigration inquiries in a timely manner and adhering to submission deadlines.
- · Keeping clients apprised of the progress of their cases.
- Reviewing applications for completeness and accuracy prior to submission to United States Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) or United States Department of Labor (DOL)
- Organizing and maintaining files related to specific cases
- Reviewing documentation received from the Client.
- Processing Labor Condition Application (LCA) for petitions.
- Legal research on case law as related to immigration
- Preparing Public Inspection File (PIF)/ Public Access File (PAF) for the filed petitions, applications and a soft copy sent to the client.
- Training other legal assistants on preparation of petitions and applications.
- Generating invoices for the clients.

Information Evolution India Private Limited (Coonoor, The Nilgiris, India)

Senior Telephone Analyst • October 2016— October 2019

- The primary task of an executive is to handle outbound calls.
- The given information should be verified accurately.
- Discuss every matter with supervisor or team leader to get any issue sorted.
- Efficiently set goals and work on so as to avoid any escalations and maintain the relevancy and quality.

Education

Providence College for Women 2012 – 2015 (Coonoor, The Nilgiris, India)

Bachelor of Commerce • June 2012 – May 2015 • Bharathiar University, Coimbatore